A long, long time ago
in the splendid East,
People toiled at dawn
and rested at dusk.
Life was filled with
peace and happiness.
However, at the end of each
year, they'd go into Hiding.
I'm the year monster.
Feed me your naughty Kids.
Not so fast.
Who should I eat first?
Maybe I'll just swallow you all.
Stop that.
On the horizon, a
warrior appeared.
Don't be scared. I
know his weakness.
He's afraid of red.
Red. Yes.
You've got to be kidding me.
Red lanterns in your Face.
Next up, couplets.
And finally...
Firecrackers. My arch enemies.
Let's light this up.
I'll be back next year.
Ever since then, at the end
of the year, people gather
Together to hang couplets,
hand out red packets,
And set off fireworks.
As the years went by, these
became our New Year Traditions.
(The Hidden Protector)
Oh, yeah.
Briar.
Yeah.
That's better.
We'll make it through
the winter with Briar here.
Briar, you're the best.
Yeah.
Wow, Briar, you're so strong.
What a catchy tune. Oh.
Briar, you're making us proud.
Boo.
That snow needs
clearing. And over there.
Briar, you said we'd celebrate
the new year together.
Come on. Imagine,
dumplings, couplets,
Firecrackers, funny, and
so many other fun things.
I can't.
Why not?
Tell me this, do animals
celebrate New Year? Can you tell?
Never. The only way
we'll show up is on a plate.
Second, our homes are
buried. There's no time to play.
If I don't help our friends,
they won't have a place to stay.
But Briar, I'm sure they'll
be just fine without you.
You can't be all
work and no play.
Huh? No play? It's a big project.
What if something goes Wrong?
I won't leave until it's done.
Oh, what could go wrong?
Would you shut your snapper?
Now go throw these away. Go.
It's not fun, but
it has to be done.
Is there anything
else we can help with?
Go help Tikky
(25 days left)
We're animals. We don't
have fun. Briar promised
he'd Celebrate the New
Year holiday with me.
But he broke his word.
I'm sorry, little Firework.
I have to throw you away.
I just want to have some fun.
What's so wrong about that?
Go away.
I said beat me... alone?
Are you a monster?
Me?
You're facing the one
who snacks on little kids.
The beast who even adults fear.
The Year Monster.
Is that really you?
In the flesh.
Go away.
So many red things. I'm
done for. Growing weak.
Really? It worked?
Gotcha.
Believe it or not, red is
actually my favorite Color.
Firework. How do you like that?
I just need something to light it.
Here
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
That's very kind of you.
Fire!
Tasty.
So let me guess, that flavor
was dragon's breath, right?
Oh.
Is this a running club?
Do you want a Drink?
Briar, help me!
Just relax.
You need my help.
Huh? You want to help me?
That's right. I
heard everything.
All you want is a little
New Year fun, right?
Yeah.
You aren't asking for much, but
Because of your
brother's nonsense,
The other animals
won't celebrate.
And you're all on your
own with no one to play with.
So sad,
So lonely.
Is this supposed to be
me? You forgot my muscles.
Anyway, you should make a pact
with me, then you'll inherit my Powers,
and you can have
whatever you want.
Well, what do you think? Is
this fancy villa to your liking?
If not- ...
How about your own
private theme park?
(Bram Vomiting)
Well, what do you think?
Place your paw print here to
Inherit the Year
Monster's powers.
Then, whatever
you want is yours.
Briar, we're headed
home. Good night, Briar.
Good night. Sleep tight,
everyone. Great job.
See you tomorrow. Let's go home
Hey, Vick.
Thanks for today.
No need to be so
formal. We're friends.
Huh. You're spending
New Year's here?
Looks like it. My parents
expect a girlfriend.
I don't want to disappoint them. I'd rather
spend New Year's here with you guys.
Hmm. Humans are complex.
All right.
Oh, I smell pretty awful.
Guess it's time for a shower.
Enjoy.
What's that?
Bram!
What's going on?
Bramble!
Wait for Me.
(laughter)
Yes! I'm finally free.
Huh?
Now it's up to
you guys. Bye bye.
Bramble. Who's she?
Bramble, your head.
Huh?
Hey.
What are those?
(Vic Grunts)
Itchy.
So itchy.
Briar, Bramble,
are you guys okay?
And who is that?
Vic, you got hair.
I have hair now?
I really have hair.
Five-ball Vic.
Look, I got antlers. They're
sticking out of my head.
Oh, let me touch them.
What's happening?
Here, touch my hair.
Bro, you got to come
feel this. It's so fluffy.
It's just like a little lamb.
Let me try.
Wait, that's not the point.
Bram, what was that?
Well, that, it was...
What? What.... what's that?
Oh,
Freezing.
Take them.
Briar, I'm scared.
Don't be. I'll keep you safe.
(Electric shock)
Briar.
Briar, say something.
Who are these people?
Where do they get their power?
If I knew we were going, I would've
brought some snacks or something.
Ah, I'm starving.
Oh, come on.
They messed up my
curly mane. Not you.
Greetings, valued guests.
Did his voice totally
change or is it just me?
Ta-da.
The voice you just heard
Was yours truly.
Sorry about your welcome.
Don't get us wrong,
We're actually the nice guys.
Come now, Robin. I've told
you before, that grim face will
Scare all the kids. Watch me.
Big Smile.
Mommy, I want to go home.
We'll work on it.
Where is the ship headed?
To a hidden realm where ordinary
Souls cannot reach.
People, Behold.
Whoa.
Think we're going to crash.
What?
What is this place?
It says something Eve?
Can't you read the plaque?
Welcome to Eve City.
About 4,000 years
ago, our ancestors
Followed the Year
Monster and settled here.
As time passed,
the city expanded.
Thanks to this realm's unique
resources, we've developed our
Own technology and culture.
Some of the residents
gained supernatural powers,
Elemental powers to be specific.
Yeah. Battery trouble.
Whoa.
But what about this place?
This is the restricted zone and
Prison of Sha.
The prison sharks?
Just Sha. No arcs.
Sha?
You failed school, didn't you?
Mm-hmm.
Didn't go.
At the beginning of time, the
Year Monster and Sha were born.
They were like fire and ice,
natural enemies fighting for Eternity.
Sha brought his army
of minions to torment
The human world. Where
they went, suffering followed.
Thankfully, the Year Monster
and her followers rose up and finally
Subdued Sha. Nevertheless,
he can't Be killed! That's why
the Year Monster's followers
built this very prison,
and Sha was sealed within it.
Ahh...
What happens if he breaks free?
The end of days.
Worldwide demise.
Don't scare them
like that. Relax.
Every New Year's Eve, the brave
lady of Eve City will take action.
With the help of the Armula,
she amplifies her power,
Driving Sha back into the seal.
Shoom, Bang, boom.
Our almighty hero,
the Year Monster, saves
the world once again.
Wait a sec. I know
that bamboozler.
Not her. The one you
met was Lady Nian.
This is her twin, Lady Sui,
in the blue, her twin sister.
Oh, I see.
I always thought that
the Year Monster was evil.
But she's no monster.
Hang on a sec. What does
that have to do with us?
Everything and more. You
have Lady Nian's powers,
so this year, you
three will seal away Sha
Huh?
Goldman, plug in port 10.
Port 10 connected.
Calibrating now.
Energy frequency is
syncing with output.
Port three, port
four. That's it!
I Finally did it.
Ramsey.
General Robin!
Is that how you
guard the library?
By handing out
the secret scroll?
I don't know.
You put Ramsey down now!
Unhand that poor boy.
I just... It's his assistant.
He's doing us a
favor by being here.
General, don't lose
your temper this time.
Goldman, Silver,
help me talk him down.
General, it's true. He's been
working on the Armula with us
Non-stop for three days.
Did you hear what he said?
Yeah, I did. Three
days of overtime.
No, not that. He said the only ones
who can seal the evil monster are you.
Maybe this is a
new type of scam.
I say we give the
powers back to them.
Wait a minute.
Oh, no!
Excuse me. If we return the Year
Monster's powers, can I keep my Hair?
Of course not.
Gotcha.
Back Uncle.
For the future of humanity,
I suggest we stay right here.
It's not about your
silly head of hair.
But Briar, look at them.
We're no match for those guys.
It looks like
We're staying.
Maybe we should
just agree for now.
They'll give us free training, and
then once we're tough enough,
we'll take all those guys
down, then be free to go.
That makes sense.
Ramsey, are you all right?
You really plan to
train those fools?
Mm, not really.
They're the backup plan.
Once we find Lady Nian,
we'll be back on track.
Don't worry. I'll get
us home all safely.
Mm-hmm. Team
Bearhug, let's do this!
You have Lady Nian's powers
within you, so it won't take long to hone
Each one of your
own elemental powers.
The elemental powers include
Thunder, wood, water,
Fire,
Earth.
The new year's almost upon us,
so our harsh training will push your
Elemental abilities
to grow even faster.
♪ Day in and day out. Shed ♪
♪ blood, sweat, no tears. ♪
♪ I train for this ♪
♪ moment. Farewell, ♪
♪ My Fears. Am I
now a true Hero? ♪
♪ Bring it on, fight
with a Smile. ♪
♪ Day in and day ♪
♪ out. I will be here. ♪
♪ I train for this ♪
♪ moment. Farewell, my Fears. ♪
♪ They'll ♪
♪ laugh at my hero's Dream. ♪
♪ So watch ♪
♪ me walk through the ♪
♪ Fire. ♪
Bramble's elemental power is
Earth.
♪ Oh, oh. Oh. Oh, oh. ♪
♪ No one can stand in my way. ♪
BRAMBLE ! BRAMBLE !
♪ Oh. Like a storm ♪
♪ that splits the sky. ♪
♪ Rolling like thunder. ♪
♪ Oh, Oh! ♪
♪ Oh. Break free from ♪
♪ hibernation. No one can stand In my way.♪
♪ Watch me dance in the fray. ♪
Vic controls the
element of thunder.
♪ drum beating ♪
♪ in my mind. Watch me ♪
♪ Fight for the day. ♪
♪ Oh you'll be Fine ♪
♪ Watch me dance in the fray. ♪
♪ Drums Beating in my mind ♪
Someone help!
♪ Watch me fight for the day. ♪
♪ The brave ♪
♪ Don't worry. ♪
♪ Day in and day
out, I Will be here. ♪
Briar, you're so cool.
Whoa.
And finally, Briar has
Unlocked the secrets of
Reminiscence?
What? Say that again.
Well, actually-
It's a power that's
useless in combat.
Anyone in Eve's City
could take you down.
Send him home. Useless, useless,
Useless, useless,
useless, useless, useless.
How dare you?
Watch me prove you wrong.
♪ Day in and day out, ♪
♪ Shed blood, sweat, no ♪
♪ tears. I've trained for this Moment. ♪
♪ Farewell, my fears. ♪
♪ Am I now a true hero? ♪
♪ Bring it on,
fight with a smile. ♪
♪ Day in and day ♪
♪ out, I will be here. ♪
♪ I've trained for this ♪
♪ moment. Farewell, my Fears. ♪
♪ Am I now a true Hero? ♪
♪ Till danger, ♪
♪ I will not run. ♪
♪ Oh, I will Fight. ♪
Good match.
You too.
Whoa.
That's amazing. I yield to you.
Yeah!
Big Bear, down here.
Down here.
Go another round with me?
Maybe next time.
He looks hurt. All that muscle,
but my teddy bear Hits harder.
(Snoring)
Well,
You're wrong.
You're wrong. You're wrong.
So yummy.
Matcha flavored.
Squad, number off. One. Two.
Three. Four. Five. Six. Seven.
Eight. Nine. 10. We
found Lady Nian in Yu City.
Let's move out.
- Sir.
(Someone grunts)
Someone...
You all right, buddy?
I can't... My glasses.
Here.
Thank you so much.
That was close.
I'm sure death by books would
make me the laughing stock of the city.
I can't thank you
enough. So who should I...
Briar?
Reminiscence is a special
power, and a rare one at that.
For millennia, only a few year
monsters have ever managed to master It.
That's not going to help.
Huh?
I'm sure I saw it
over here. Found it.
Here it is. This is it, the only
manual for mastering reminiscence.
Well,
You got it wrong. I want something
like hoa, hoa for fighting, to
Prepare me for battle.
Briar, your power
is really unique.
Master it, and you'll be
able to work wonders.
All right then.
Ever since Lady Cui passed away
last year, our city's been a mess.
Huh?
She died?
You really don't know.
During the battle to seal
Sha last year, Lady Cui
Was...
Everyone said Lady
Nian ran away out of fear,
But I think it was
actually her broken heart.
Hey, Ramsay. What
does this book say?
The words themselves
don't matter.
Do you see these pictures? Follow
the drawings and you'll do fine.
This here says, "Practicing with the
armilla can speed up your Training."
Armilla.
That golden device?
You got it.
The armilla is the
crown jewel of Eve's City.
It unlocks the year
monster's true power.
Every lord and lady uses
the armilla to seal away the
Mighty Sha every single
new year, time and Again.
Ramsay, General wants you.
Coming. Take your
time. I've got to go.
Oh,
Briar, if you need more
help, I've got your back.
Ramsay, watch out!
See you around.
The armilla.
Hey, it's Briar.
I'm just here to train.
I won't cause trouble.
These moves serve as a guide.
They can bring your mind
into a calm and selfless state.
Only then can you connect
with the world and gain clarity
That's good. And
raise this hand.
Once you've mastered your
mind, you won't need these moves
Anymore.
Huh? It worked. Wait,
what can I try it on?
What the...
Oh.
So,
Why have you called me out
here if there's nothing to say?
It's you. You tricked
Bramble. All of this is your fault.
What is this? Huh?
I've always wondered,
Why were two year
monsters born instead of one?
Oh.
Oh. Oh.
I don't know what part
you're meant to play.
You're more human
Than year monster.
Your heart rules your mind.
What is this? Oh.
Oh.
As Sha's power grows stronger,
I feel my grip slipping.
What is this thing?
Perhaps we're all wrong.
Farewell, Nian.
That memory
Was reminiscence?
I still don't get
how It's useful. Huh?
All year monsters use
this to amplify your powers.
I guess now that also
includes me. Just one touch.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
Going on a test drive.
Taking a shortcut
won't get me Anywhere
Come on, Briar. It's shameful.
But
As I am now,
How can I protect them?
If I'm going to bring them
home safely, I need more power.
Wait, I'm not ready.
It's working.
Power is surging through me.
What? No. No, no, no. No,
No. I made a mistake.
Code
Black! The seal's broken! What
happened? What happened?
Oh, dear. What's happening?
Somebody get them. Help!
The Armilla.
Oh. Oh.
Briar,
Briar Watch out!
Ramsey.
Stay back.
It's the Armilla. Something's
wrong with it. Go.
Find Lady Nian
and bring her back.
You. Look at what you have done.
Move it!
Find Lady Nian
and bring her back.
Briar!
Briar, up here!
Come to safety.
Follow me to the city gate.
Hurry, cover our flank.
Where is he going?
Don't ask me.
No, not anymore. We're
under orders to find Lady Nian.
Sha's energy is
flooding out. Go!
Go!
Destination, Yew City.
Press the button to depart.
Destination, Yew
City. Press the button...
How have I made such a mess?
(3 Days Left)
No way.
There's so many people.
How am I going to find her?
Whoa.
Awesome! Cool!
Wow! Check it out!
It's falling Apart.
Oh Man.
Whoo-hoo!
Phew. Phew.
There's a fire.
Huh?
I've got you.
Bye-bye.
No!
Hey, you can't run.
Eddy! Lend me your board.
Hold on. Don't
break it this time.
Be careful.
Move! Don't block the road!
It's an actual emergency!
Ugh, for heaven's sake.
Mrs. Chao, Mr. Li,
better luck today.
Look who's here. Want to play?
I'm not playing with
you. You guys cheat.
Don't threaten the lady
Eve City is in real trouble.
I can't hear you.
She's gone.
Split up.
Where Are you?
Hey, little doggy.
So you also want to play.
Ugh, it's the same game of tag
Every day, but I'm still faster.
Huh?
Fun time's over.
Eve City's in danger.
No, thanks. Don't wanna.
I'll let someone else
deal with that mess.
You can't be serious.
The one we need is you.
Eve City's been fun.
Where to go next?
I could check out Shen City
Or Lao City.
Hmm, that decides it. Shen City.
The Armilla exploded.
Huh? What did you say?
The Armilla's
Broken.
What?
Medic, quick, get over here.
He's been poisoned.
To the clinic, go!
It's a disaster.
Well, boys, I need
an update like now.
Sir, the Armilla's
beyond our help now.
There's just one other fix.
That requires the
blood of a Year Monster.
We've got to track
down Lady Nian, pronto.
There's more. The repair
gummies are almost out.
Someone has to collect them.
How?
When it rains, it pours. You think
anyone's just standing around?
Huh
Briar, dude, I thought
I was doing a bad job.
The Armilla has stood for a
millennial and you just broke it ?
Do you have any idea what
Sha could do to the world, do you
I messed up. I just
wanted to... Hold on.
You're the Lady of Eve
City. You're the Year Monster.
This was your mess to begin with. If you
hadn't made false promises to Bramble,
This wouldn't have happened.
Oh, all right, fine.
Huh?
I'll go back with
you and fix this.
Really?
Let's be clear, once
the Armilla's fixed,
You'll have to
figure out the rest.
As long as it's fixed,
I'll handle the rest.
Deal?
Deal.
Hurry! Stop him!
Oh, that looks nice.
I'll take two.
Uh, Nian.
This isn't the way that I took.
What's going on?
There's just one more
thing to take care of.
Is it that important? The
new year is two days away.
Huh? She was just here.
For goodness sake.
I'm not letting you...
Sorry. Wrong person.
Wrong person? Yeah, right.
Nian! Nian! Nian!
Keep it down.
Embarrassing.
Well, come on.
All this way for a bag of junk?
What do you know? We need
them to find repair gummies.
Gummies?
Lucky I hid two sets. The gummies
stored in Eve City won't Cut it this time.
Here, put them on.
Oh.
See those glowing beacons?
They'll lead us to repair gummies.
So, what's repair a gummy?
When different objects are well
used and well loved, they absorb
Positive energy from the people they
touch, and repair gummies form within.
Sweetheart, your dinner's ready.
No, five more minutes.
I'll give you five minutes.
No! Mom, you haven't
started counting.
Clear.
With this plunger, we'll pull the gummies
out without even breaking a sweat.
Maybe I should do it.
Zip it.
Well, don't just stand
there. Catch them.
This gummy,
It looks like Sunny.
Quick, put them in.
Once this bag's full, we should
have enough to fix the Armilla.
Come on then, onto the next one.
Oh.
Catch!
Take off that mask!
Come back here!
I'll fight you.
Oh.
I'll
Swoop the little guy. Good idea.
Come on.
(baby Cries)
You Big bully.
Whoa. (Baby laughs)
There's gummies here,
But this color looks strange.
Let me check.
Hey,
Quit fussing.
Ugh, fine. Go ahead.
You Miserable thieves.
Hands off my gummies.
Who did that?
Briar?
Briar!
I knew it. I knew you
wouldn't run away.
It's Lady Liar.
Stop calling me a
liar. The name's Nian.
Liar.
- Hey, what are you doing here?
All the soldiers are after Ramsey,
so we had to find the repair gummies.
Look, we almost
filled this whole bag.
It was my fault that
Ramsey got hurt.
Don't worry. Ramsey will be
fine. He just needs some treatment.
Really? What a relief.
Are you going to chat all
night, or come and help me?
Sorry, we're coming.
Just a little more.
Looks like I used
too much power.
No more helping Vic.
Hmm. The gummies
just won't come out.
And why's that?
No idea.
Did something
happen to this family?
The power of
reminiscence would help.
Huh? Huh? Reminiscent?
Huh?
Huh
Don't get your hopes up.
Look at my kite.
It flies so high.
Slow down.
Mommy, Daddy, watch this. Wee.
(laughter)
Daddy, Mommy, look
at this snowman I made.
All by yourself?
- Daddy, Mommy, please can you stay home a Few more days?
Martin.
Martin, your mommy and
daddy are coming back tomorrow
for New Year's.
Aren't you happy?
Hmm. It's been three years.
I don't need them anymore.
How could you say
that? Don't be silly.
Millicent!
Mr. Kyle.
It's terrible. Your son and
his wife were caught in a
Landslide. They're
missing. Please stay calm.
The whole village
is out searching.
How can I be calm?
I'm coming with you.
Oh, no.
That boy,
He's in danger.
Help
Us.
Help. Amelia. Help.
Amelia.
Are you okay?
Where are you?
Daddy.
Mommy, where did you go?
Someone help me.
The forest is too vast.
Split up now.
Got it.
Lucky I'm fast.
Uh-oh. See you later.
Hey, wait for me, Vick.
Not here.
Not here either.
Right there.
Somebody help.
Is anyone there?
Help us.
Someone's trapped.
Oh, no, it's
collapsing. Bramble!
Thank goodness.
Huh?
He's all right.
We're here to save you Martin.
Got you.
Bramble! Bram, there's
people. Come quick.
Come with me. Huh?
Everything hurts,
and I'm hungry.
Huh?
Whoa.
Vick, slow down.
Vick,
Can't you slow down?
Honey.
Bee!
Vick, Don't slow down!
Your face freaked Him out.
You're one to talk.
You mean I'm the scary one?
I'll show you. I'm all teeth
And eyes.
Wee.
She dropped me. Get back here.
Huh?
My Bag.
Okay.
There you are.
Monster.
You call me a monster?
You little brat. What
did you call me?
Don't you think I'm cute?
Stop chasing me.
Just leave me alone.
I'm only little.
Watch out.
I'm Coming.
I've got you.
Help. It's harsh, people.
Hmph. I run from nothing.
Let go of me!
What were you thinking coming
into the forest alone? You're just a kid.
If we weren't here, you
would've been done for.
I Can't find my mommy and daddy.
Everyone just Says they're working
far away, and now they're missing,
and I Can't find them.
It's all right.
Don't cry, Martin.
I really want to see them again.
I know. We'll make sure
we find your mom and dad.
Honey,
Do you see this, too?
Daddy!
Huh?
Mommy!
Daddy. Mommy.
Martin!
My boy.
I'm so happy you're okay.
Look.
This is all my pocket
money. I saved all of it in here.
Mommy, Daddy, please, I want
you to stay home with me Now.
Martin.
Oh, we are not going anywhere.
I'm going to cry.
Nian.
Let's go.
Uh-huh.
This time we'll get them out.
Oh.
Yeah!
Hey, don't bite my butt.
It's on me.
Hold still.
Coming, buddy.
Whoa,
Knock it off.
What? It wasn't me.
Sure it wasn't.
The first rays of the
morning sun. I feel refreshed.
Hey, Nian, do you come to
the human world very often?
Yes. I love hanging around
here. There's so much to do,
So much to eat.
People feel so deeply
here. They're so full of Life.
Just like you three, always
laughing and then crying.
It's wonderful. Right, Bram?
You get what I mean, right?
Crybaby.
I never cried. My
eyes got sand in them.
Whoa. It's lucky the sand picked the right
time, just as you were feeling Emotional.
So wonderful.
Bram, don't go. Help me, too.
I think I feel sand in my Eyes.
Nian,
I'm sorry.
Huh?
I had you all wrong.
It's no big deal. I get it a lot.
Briar, you need to Lighten up.
Huh.
But I don't understand. Why'd
you give up your Powers?
That's not the Nian I know.
Because
Anyone could do a
better job than I can.
I'll just mess it up.
Why would you think
that? I think you're great.
Go easy on yourself. You...
Huh?
Ramsey?
That's...
General Robin? What's he doing?
Maybe Ramsey just wanted
some fresh air for his treatment.
Makes sense. They say
even though he looks scary,
that inside He's
actually a big softie.
You. Are you here to interfere?
Well, we, uh...
Huh?
Hmm.
Briar?
Shh.
Oh, we're, uh... We're
here for repair gummies.
Yeah. Take a look. Actually,
we're heading back to Eve City.
We heard the commotion,
and we came to check it Out.
Ahh
Then what's your excuse?
You caught me. You'll
have to take me down. Yah!
Wait, General.
I've got
The moves for this.
Briar, maybe we misunderstood. I think
we should turn back and Reason with him.
Didn't you see? He wasn't holding
back. I told you he's not a good guy.
Hand over the fugitive.
Briar, get back.
We'll handle this.
Come and catch me
if you can, Grandpa.
As planned, I'm good. Huh?
Hmm?
Ah.
I know all your
moves, so come at me.
Did that work?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Come on, Nian. Think, think.
Don't.
Your nonsense ends now. Hold on.
Let them go.
I'll come back with you,
Master.
(1 Day Left)
Quick, prepare for
emergency surgery.
Who would do this to him?
It was General Robin.
What?
Oh, that makes
sense. At least he alive.
I know now that
everything you did
Was to make me stronger.
I didn't understand
that at the time.
The Armilla.
You're aware, then.
The Armilla, it rejected them
And exploded,
Because they are not
the real Year Monster.
Those before you
Learned that becoming a guardian
Meant sacrifice,
Even their own life.
I can see you have a
lot on your shoulders,
But this duty
Is yours and yours alone.
This time,
I won't run away.
No one knows why,
But two Year Monsters
were born that year,
For the first time
in our history.
Sui, Sui. Here, I
made this for you.
Look, it matches my
necklace. Pretty, right?
I got a big one.
As Sui and I grew older,
I realized how different
we had become.
(Growls)
Everyone's saying it. Without
her sister here, what would she do?
Yeah, I guess. Watching her
training tells you that much.
I ran away from Eve City.
I left everything
for Sui to shoulder.
The repaired gummies are ready!
Gummy Integration, begin.
Please, little gummies,
we need this to work.
General.
What's wrong?
Clinic.
After you return your
powers, you can all go home,
And you can leave
The rest to me.
Mm.
Ramsay,
I'm glad I get to say
goodbye. Thank you for...
Easy there.
You're hurt. Let's get
you back to the clinic.
Take a look,
Briar.
My precious hair.
It'll be fine, Vick.
You're not young.
Even if you kept your powers,
you'd lose your hair anyway.
Ah.
Well, I mean,
You had it once,
in your memories.
Briar, Vick, watch out!
Ah.
That's Ramsey?
Someone help! They need help.
Are you all right? What
happened up there?
It's something bad.
What's going on? What happened?
I blacked Out.
(Grunts)
Ramsey, what are you doing?
Only Year Monsters can
unlock the Armilla's Powers.
My years in that library have shown me
it has the power to harness Sha's energy.
It actually worked.
My theory was correct.
I will be the
strongest of them all.
The scroll is ruined,
and the Armilla is broken.
You're the only obstacle left.
Please allow me
To finish you off.
1...2...
1...2... It won't budge an inch.
Who says so?
One thing's true,
I'll strike through.
Sorry, old door.
Lightning fast, Vick.
Your time is due.
Incoming!
I knew it. There were
too many coincidences.
I should've dealt
with you sooner.
I guess you were
right about me all along.
This mess really is my making.
As for your Lieutenants,
I finished them off.
You fiend.
When I wanted a teacher, I
begged you, but you brushed me Off.
I'll surpass you soon, and
you'll drown in Your self-pity.
In Your dreams.
Master!
Master.
Time has dulled you.
Nian, get out!
Once the Year Monster is gone-
Nian!
... I'll be invincible.
Master.
Ramsey!
Oh, you're despicable.
Now you wanna
play the hero briar?
Your selfish desire for power is
what unlocked Sha's Darkness.
It's you who broke the Armilla
and saved Me from Robin.
We both want to be the
strongest. You're no better than
I am. Just look at yourself!
Nian,
What I care about most
Is you.
But my torch has flickered.
Please,
Don't go. From now on,
You'll light your own way.
Master.
No!
Bramble, hop on!
Next to Ramsey!
No
I left Eve City
And my duty to Sui.
In the end,
I lost my sister
And my master, too.
I've finally done it. I've made
myself the most Powerful.
Nian!
It's Not empty Anymore!
- Run! - Fire...
Ramsey was right.
This is all my fault.
I can't accept it.
I was always the
protector among us three,
But here,
They're protecting me.
Even worse, I've
caused them harm.
So,
Nian,
Don't blame yourself.
It's my fault.
(Rattling sound) uh
Sui.
What should I do?
(Gleam sound of bells)
This is my sister's
bracelet. So why is it Here?
Oh,
Wait.
What the...
A mural. Of what?
It looks like the story
of the first year monster.
But after so
long, it's not clear.
Huh.
Why was Sui here?
Huh?
It's going to blow.
Briar, use your power.
Sui knew something.
She must be trying
to tell us. Quick.
Huh?
Briar! Hurry!
ugh
Sui.
Oh.
Nian.
What's wrong?
Soldiers, charge!
Ram, let's go.
Fire!
As if Ram Sey wasn't strong
enough, now we summoned An army?
We're doomed.
Bramble, pick.
Briar.
Lady Nian.
Nian.
We were worried about you.
Somehow we're fine.
- I'm Fine.
Goldman,
Lend me your pocket watch.
Briar, this is No time to
play with your pocket watch.
We found a mural that'll
help us take Sha down.
What? So there's still a way?
Still there, we're toast.
And not the butter kind.
(Train sound)
No Naughty boy escapes from Me
Avonda,
Hey!
(People shouts in attack mode)
I never doubted
you for a second.
It's no time for tears.
I want a piece of this.
Briar, what's your plan?
- We're going
To find Ramsey.
All right.
Easy on the eyes.
Wait up, Vick.
Why don't you just
take a breather?
Nian.
- Briar.
Briar. Briar.
Stay Away.
My
Curly crown.
Don't call me - Hey Bram,
they just called you fat.
How dare you?
Say that again.
You singed my hair!
Say something nice.
So I'll singe you.
Or say nothing at all.
You got that?
Called me huggable.
Oh, yeah.
Ninefold lightning whip.
Vick. Those hips don't
lie. That was my Warm-up.
Vick, your hair. It's...
Stop laughing right now.
Get off Chitchat.
I need help up here.
Hey, big birdie.
Now look up here
Ha.
Mr. Teddy Bear,
pull yourself together.
Hey, cut it out. I'm no teddy.
Briar, are you all right?
- I'm good.
Vick, Bram, this time I
need you to protect Me.
Okay, let's go.
Watch Out!
My lady.
Your turn, Vick.
What's that move called?
Have I seen it before?
Bramble.
Split.
It's Not fair.
It's not fair. It's not fair.
Ramsey.
It's not fair. It's
not fair. It's not fair.
Ramsey.
It's not fair. It's not fair.
I've always worked
harder than anyone.
I just wanted to be strong, a
man who could guard Eve City.
I practiced day and
night. I worked so hard
Harder than anyone else.
Yet I still turned out to be
a useless, pathetic Clerk.
And all of this is
the general's fault.
I begged him for so long,
yet he never took me seriously.
(people laughing)
Their laughter still stings.
Ramsey, that's not true.
I understand you.
When I came to Eve City, I also
felt like everyone saw me as useless.
But then I clicked,
there's more than one way to protect everyone.
So I decided to let go of my Obsession.
It showed me I have
friends I could count on,
And so much else to give.
Ramsey, take a break.
Share a snack with us.
I know
You're not a bad person.
Just come home.
I'll bring you back.
Come on.
It's just too late now.
Ramsey. No.
No.
Ramsey.
Where's My bottle?
Darling, Can you make a bottle?
My boss just sent me
an email. Do it yourself.
Mommy, my car won't move.
- Mommy, I want my bottle now.
Okay.
You've been lying
there the whole day.
No cleaning, ignoring the kids.
I shouldn't have married you.
Oh, marrying you. I'm
the one paying our bills.
Do you have any idea how hard I
work? Marrying you was my mistake.
What's taking so long? We
haven't moved. My family is waiting.
Sorry, sir, it's the weather.
Then make a plan.
I told you, it's the weather. I can't
control it. I want to go home, too.
You're about to be 30 years old. All of our
friends have grandkids that are already On the way,
but you, you don't
even have a boyfriend.
Enough. I won't
live through this.
She came back to see all of
us. Why would you say that?
Don't bother
The New Year's bell is about to
ring. Let's count down Together.
Briar, what do we do now?
- 9
Hold on.
8.. 7 ..6...5
3....2.....1.... Nian
I'm leaving the rest to you.
At the beginning of time, the
Year Monster and Sha Were born.
While Sha causes only disasters,
the Year Monster
brings hope of new life.
Ancient tribes fought
endlessly to conquer,
Manifesting masses of dark
energy which fed Sha's power,
Bringing calamity
to the human world.
The Year Monster held
fast against it, but was no
Match for Sha.
After being saved, the
Year Monster discovered
those who survived, although not
related, cared deeply for one Another,
standing shoulder to shoulder.
The hopeful energy created
by their unity healed Her,
Unlocking a new
way to defeat Sha.
She turned into a fearsome
beast who chased villagers,
Threatening to eat them. She spread
rumors of her Weaknesses to humans
, her fear of the color
red and Firecrackers.
People came together.
They forgot their grudges, worked
together, and drove Away the monster.
All the courage, happiness,
love, and other joyous
Emotions turned into vast
energy, which flowed into
the Year Monster,
empowering her against Sha
And bringing
brightness to humankind.
Thanks to the first Year Monster,
people gather Together for the new year.
Here.
Your mom made this.
Your generation
thinks differently.
I'm getting old.
I'm sorry. I just hope
that you'll be happy.
That's all we want.
And if you're struggling,
we're just a phone call away.
Your mom and I
will always pick up.
All right, I get it.
Honey.
Well,
I'm sorry
For today. I'll do the chores
so you can breathe. How's that?
Inho,
You've been working so hard.
Instead, we'll do them
together. All right?
None of you are making
it. Well, all right then.
How about we
celebrate together then?
Check it out, I've got
sausages for days.
How nice, sweetie.
Candy, anyone?
Here, have a handful.
I've got snacks, too. -So do I.
- Thank you. You're so generous. -Help yourself.
I've got a surprise. We've prepared
enough piping hot dumplings for Everyone.
Who's hungry? Huh?
Please, let me help.
Then I'll push.
Okay. Here. Who wants dumplings?
Careful. It's hot.
Ooh, I'll have some.
Who's hungry?
Come on, dinner's ready.
Hey, Dad, let's
go to the cinema.
Do I have to sit through
another cartoon?
Daddy, Mommy.
Come, honey. Let's
make a snowman.
I'll make a big snow bear.
Sweetie, look who's
here. It's your daddy.
Nana. Fly with delayed .
- I missed you so much. -Oh, my dear.
Cheese.
Daddy, I want to
put this one up.
All right.
Nian.
I hope you know
That all of us can clearly see
how deeply you care for everyone.
You're endlessly patient,
feeling all their sorrows and Joys.
If I were asked who
could save the world,
I'd say
Nian.
You love this world
more than anyone.
Perhaps we're all wrong.
I think your gentle heart makes
you more Year Monster than anyone.
For thousands of years, like
rivers flowing into Oceans,
humankind's joy and
happiness flooded together,
becoming the source of
the Year Monster's powers.
Huh? Briar, did you
know this would happen?
Yes. This is the real
power of a year monster.
(Building cinematic
theme music )
Long live the year monster!
Thank you, Briar.
Ooh, yeah.
Huh?
Fireworks.
(People Cheering)
Daddy. Get up,
it's the new year!
It's the first day of the new
year. Best wishes to our listeners.
Make sure you say
hello to everyone.
Grandpa!
- Yeah.
Happy New Year!
We're 30 minutes away.
Uncle, we're almost there.
Granny! Oh, my handsome
boy. I've missed you.
I missed you.
Happy new year.
Happy New Year!